.
>> good afternoon.
Welcome to the APRIL 22nd 2025
regular meeting of the san
francisco board of supervisors.
>> MADAM Clerk, will you please
call the roll?
Thank you, MR. PRESIDENT.
Supervisor chan chan PRESIDENT
Supervisor chen chen present
supervisor dorsey dorsey
present supervisor engardio
and engardio present supervisor
fielder fielder present
supervisor mahmood hope mahmood
not present a supervisor
mandolin PRESIDENT Mandolin
PRESIDENT Supervisor melgar
melgar present supervisor sadr
sadr present supervisor cheryl
sherrell present and supervisor
walton walton present.
>> MR. PRESIDENT, you have a
quorum.
Thank you, MADAM Clerk.
The san francisco board of
supervisors acknowledges that
we are on the unceded ancestral
homeland of the rahmatullah
aloni who are the original
inhabitants of the san
francisco peninsula.
As the indigenous stewards of
this land and in accordance
with their traditions the
rama to saloni have never ceded
lost nor forgotten their
responsibility as the
caretakers of this place as
well as for all peoples who
reside in their traditional
territory.
As guests we recognize that we
benefit from living and working
on their traditional homelands.
We wish to pay our respects by
acknowledging the ancestors,
elders and relatives of the
romita aloni community and by
affirming their sovereign
rights as first peoples.
Colleagues, will you join me
in reciting the pledge of
allegiance?
I pledge allegiance to the flag
of the united states of america
and to the republic for which
it stands one nation under GOD,
indivisible, with liberty
and justice for all.
On behalf of the board I would
like to acknowledge the staff
at S.F. Gov tv today
particularly kaleena mendoza
who record each of our meetings
and make the transcripts
available to the public online
.
>> MADAM Clerk, do you have any
communications?
Yes, thank you, MR. PRESIDENT.
The san francisco board of
supervisors welcomes you to
attend this meeting in person
in the board's legislative
chamber within city hall second
floor room 250.
Or if you can't make it to the
chamber, you can watch the
proceeding on S.F. Gop tv's
channel 26 or view the
livestream at w w w dot S.F.
Govee tv.Org.
If you have public comment
you'd like to submit in writing
you can submit an email to be
offset S.F. Gov dawg or send it
via the us postal service to
the san francisco board of
supervisors.
The number one DR. Carlton b
goodland place city hall room
244 san francisco california
94102.
If you would like to make a
reasonable accommodation
request under the americans
with disability act or if you
need to request language
assistance, contact the clerk's
office at least two business
days in advance by calling
(415) 554-5184.
Thank you, MR. PRESIDENT.
Thank you, MADAM Clerk.
Let's go to our approval of our
meeting minutes.
Approval of the MARCH 18th 2025
board meeting minutes.
>> all right, colleagues, do we
have any changes to these
meeting minutes?
I don't see anybody on the
roster so MAY I have a motion
to approve the minutes as
presented moved by melgar,
seconded by walton.
MADAM Clerk, will you please
call the roll on the minutes
supervisor chin chin I
supervisor dorsey dorsey I
supervisor and engardio
and engardio I supervisor
fielder fielder I supervisor
mahmood mahmood I supervisor
randleman hi randleman I
supervisor melgar melgar I
supervisor sartor sartor I
supervisor cheryl cheryl I
supervisor walton walton I
and supervisor chen chan I
there are 11 eyes without
objection the minutes will be
approved after public comment
as presented MADAM Clerk let's
go to our consent to agenda
items one through five items
one through five are on
consent.
These items are considered to
be routine but if a member
objects an item MAY be removed
and considered separately.
>> I don't see anyone on the
roster MADAM Clerk can you
please call the roll on items
one through five supervisor
chen chin eyes supervisor
dorsey dorsey I supervisor
and engardio and engardio I
supervisor fielder fielder I
supervisor mahmood mahmood I
supervisor mandolin I mandolin
I supervisor melgar melgar I
supervisor sadr sadr I
supervisor cheryl cheryl I
supervisor walton walton I
and supervisor chen chan either
are lebanese without objection
these ordinances are finally
passed.
>> MADAM Clerk, can you please
take us to our regular agenda
unfinished business item number
six item six this is an
ordinance to approve and waive
competitive solicitation
obligations for a port
commission park lease and loan
for china basin park and for a
management agreement for
adjacent public and open spaces
between the port and an
affiliate of seawall lot 337
associates llc developer of the
mission rock project and to
approve a port commission
license with mission rock
utilities inc and approved to
port commission licenses
and and absolving services
agreement with pacific gas
and electric company to
facilitate gas services to
private property in the project
area and electric power service
to the third street bridge
pilot house and to affirm the
secret determination and to
make the appropriate findings
we can take this item same
house, same call.
>> without objection this
ordinance is finally passed.
MADAM Clerk let's go to new
business.
please call item seven
and eight together.
>> item seven and eight are two
resolutions that authorize
grants for the recreation
and parks department.
Item seven authorizes a grant
agreement with wu yi children's
services to accept and expend
cash or in-kind grants from wu
yi children's services valued
at approximately 1.125 million
for the tenderloin recreation
center children's playground
improvement projects and for
item eight this item authorizes
a grant agreement with kaboom
and to accept and expend cash
and or in-kind grants from
kaboom.
Valued at approximately 5
million to support improvements
for up to eight children's play
spaces sites let's take these
items same house same call
without objection these
resolutions are adopted.
>> MADAM Clerk can you please
call item nine?
Item nine this ordinance was
referred without recommendation
from the land use
and transportation committee.
It amends the planning code to
require notice of rezoning
intended to comply with housing
element law and to affirm the
second determination and to
make the appropriate findings.
>> supervisor dorsey thank you
PRESIDENT Randleman colleagues
I'll confess this was this item
was a close call for me because
I do understand and support
generally the imperative of
public transparency
and democracy at the end of the
day however, I think just even
in the last hour I think the
noticing requirement marks a
departure from precedents I'm
aware of including the up
zoning that took place in the
eastern neighborhoods many of
which I represent.
So in good conscience I'm going
to oppose this now in my view
to live in a major american
city today, especially in a
city like ours that is
afflicted with a crisis
in housing affordability
and access reflecting an issue
that is routinely rated among
voters as the issue number 1 or
2, it is to know that we have
an obligation to affirmatively
for further fair housing.
I think this notice requirement
is potentially needlessly
alarming, overly prescriptive
and a departure from past
presidents precedent and that's
why I'm not going to be
supporting it next supervisor
melgar thank you PRESIDENT
Mandell men colleagues I was
going to explain that this item
left the land use committee
without recommendation so that
it could be voted on by the
full board.
I also will not be supporting
it.
I think that it sets a
problematic precedent.
We have never done this kind of
notification and for any
rezoning that we've done in the
city and this is certainly not
the first it's not going to be
the last and you know, I fear
that it just adds to sort of
climate and conversation that
has been alarming needlessly
when there are legitimate
issues that arise from any
rezoning, we can solve those
issues and I don't think that
that you know, is done by
alarming folks unnecessarily
and so I think that there can
be transparency that can be
sharing of information.
I think the planning department
certainly has done that.
>> but we didn't do this type
of notification when we did the
eastern neighborhoods plan.
We didn't do it with central
soma.
We didn't do it with a
shipyard.
We didn't do it when we down
zoned all of the western
neighborhoods.
And so I don't see a need to do
it today.
>> thank you.
Supervisor chan thank you
PRESIDENT Man domain at land
use colleagues and I use last
week it was a lot of discussion
on why we should pass this
ordinance but I want to say
that at the committee and the
committee really failed to
recognize intent of this
legislation which is to let san
franciscans know about upcoming
major changes that would affect
our residents landlords
and business communities across
the city.
It is according to the planning
department that up you know,
upcoming rezoning plan could
impact at least 13,000 acres of
san francisco land where
roughly about 30,000 acres.
So as you can imagine and out
of which 4000 acres is
parkland.
>> so more than half of san
francisco will be impacted.
So the fact that we didn't have
notification and previous
redevelopment and urban renewal
project is not a valid reason
to stop us from doing what is
right today in 2025.
In fact, even with government
agencies overseeing the
previous development
and redevelopment project, we
hear from communities time
and time again even today that
they would like to see more
information and more outreach
city planning policies are
complex concepts that are
challenging to even convey
in english.
So imagine how many families
and individuals we're leaving
behind in monolingual
and vulnerable communities.
So to that I say our solution
in san francisco should always
be to do more, not less
especially under this federal
administration where censorship
of information has already been
weaponized to silence
and manipulate the masses
optimally.
The goal of the housing element
is to increase affordable
housing which I support.
>> this ordinance does not
contradict that mission
and only promotes participate
ation of the housing element
but most importantly our
community's right to know what
is happening and impacting them
.
Then again this legislation is
simply notifying residents,
business and property owners
that will be impacted by the
upcoming rezoning plan that
will impact them within 300ft
of their property and where
they reside and where they
conduct business.
So it is a simple,
straightforward right to know
legislation.
I truly to hope to have your
support today.
>> thank you.
Supervisor chen hi colleagues.
>> I also want to express my
strong support for the goal of
ensuring that our city is
providing adequate notice to
the residents whose properties
will be affected by the
rezoning and I believe a very
successful rezoning program
comes about with good planning
and that requires impacted
communities to receive
sufficient notice and have the
opportunity to also inform the
proposals moving forward.
>> and I also just want to
clarify in the in the land use
committee I had hoped that we
could move forward to the item
with positive recommendation
and that's why I did not
support a motion to advance
this legislation with that
recommendation and I am a
co-sponsor of this legislation
and and will continue to vote
yes to support this ordinance
today.
>> thank you.
>> supervisor fielder thank you
.
>> I think this is a common
sense measure rooted
in transparency, equity
and basic democratic principles
in our planning processes.
It doesn't stop rezoning.
It simply says if we're going
to change the rules for entire
neighborhoods, the people who
live and run small businesses
there deserve to know.
To me that's basic responsible
governance and community
engagement.
>> so I appreciate supervisor
chan for bringing this
legislation forward and I will
be supporting it.
>> thank you.
Supervisor fielder.
>> MADAM Clerk, please call the
roll an item nine supervisor
chin chin eyes supervisor
dorsey dorsey no supervisor
and engardio and engardio I
supervisor fielder fielder I
supervisor mahmood mahmood no
supervisor mandelson I
randleman I supervisor melgar
no melgar no supervisor sadr
sadr I supervisor cheryl cheryl
I supervisor walton walton I
and supervisor chen shan I
there are eight eyes and three
nose with supervisor dorsey
mahmood and melgar voting no
this ordinance is passed on
first reading MADAM Clerk can
you please call item ten?
>> item ten this is an
ordinance to amend the
administrative code to allow
city departments to purchase
content and data subscriptions
without complying with
solicitation requirements that
would otherwise apply
and without adhering to
provisions in the municipal
code that impose obligations on
contracting parties as a
condition to agreement with the
city and to list conditions
required for amendment or
modification portion of such
agreements.
>> MADAM Clerk, please call the
roll on item ten.
Supervisor chen chen I
supervisor dorsey dorsey I
supervisor orange engardio
and engardio I supervisor
fielder fielder I supervisor
mahmood mahmood I supervisor
mandolin hi mendelson I
supervisor melgar melgar I
supervisor sadr sadr i
supervisor cheryl cheryl I
supervisor walton walton I
and supervisor chen chin either
are 11 eyes without objection
this ordinance is passed on
first reading MADAM Clerk let's
go to committee reports yes
committee reports items 11
and 12 were considered by the
land use and transportation
committee at a regular meeting
on monday APRIL 21st and were
forwarded out as committee
reports item 11 this ordinance
was recommended as amended but
with the same title it amends
the planning code and the
zoning map to establish the
3250 19th avenue special sign
district to provide signage
opportunities commensurate with
the size of the parcel and to
affirm the second determination
and to make the requisite
findings.
>> all right, let's take this
same house, same call.
Without objection, the
ordinance is passed on first
reading MADAM Clerk, please
call item 12 item 12 this was
recommended as a committee
report.
>> it's an ordinance to amend
the planning code to remove the
conditional use authorization
for formula retail uses in the
residential commercial zoning
districts along venice avenue
four lots fronting venice
avenue and to establish that a
change of ownership or operator
of a preexisting formula retail
use that has not previously
received a conditional youth
use authorization is not an
intensification of such use
that would require conditional
use authorization and to affirm
the second determination and to
end the requisite findings.
>> supervisor cheryl thank you
PRESIDENT Mendelson colleagues
this legislation takes a major
step towards reducing barriers
to filling commercial
vacancies.
First this ordinance
principally permits formulary
retail along venice between
chestnut and broadway venice is
facing a crisis of persistent
commercial vacancies.
Planning department surveys
found a 53% ground floor
commercial vacancy rate on
venice compared to the rest of
the city's 7.7 vacancy rate or
even union square's shockingly
high 22% vacancy rate.
The 50% vacancy rates on venice
are a crisis.
Since taking office I have
heard from many building owners
on venice who are replete with
stories of tenants deterred
potential tenants deterred by
the on average seven and a half
month long permitting timeline
.
This is bad for van ness
and it's bad for the city as a
whole because with so many road
users this street has an
outsized impact on public
perception of the city's
economic health.
We should be helping fill these
vacancies not standing in the
way especially when this change
is in line with the history of
vanessa's commercial identity.
At history includes large
retailers and chain stores on
the street and despite a
decline in tenants now in its
third decade.
>> our planning code currently
requires protective form
prospective formula retail
stores to navigate multi-month
long conditional use processes.
If we know these spaces are
hard to fill, why are we making
it harder?
We need to be doing all that we
can to make it easier to open
stores.
We need to increase flexibility
with van ness which this
ordinance will do helping
activate vacant spaces
and breathe new life into this
corridor at the heart of the
city.
Second and perhaps most
importantly, this ordinance
will eliminate the requirement
for new formula retail
operators to obtain a
conditional use authorization
if the previous formula retail
operator at the location did
not possess a q a for formula
retail.
Well why is this important?
For me this is important
because it will directly impact
the former safeway on fillmore.
Since the fillmore safeway
opened before formula retail
controls were enacted it never
obtained one meaning any new
grocery classified as formula
retail must secure a
conditional use authorization.
If we want a grocery store to
replace a grocery store we
should probably make it easier
to open a grocery store.
I'm excited that this
streamlining provision will
help fill numerous other
vacancies left by prior formula
retail tenants.
And I'm grateful that this
legislation is co-sponsored by
supervisor sadr supervisor
mahmood and supervisor melgar
and that it has the support of
all of the local small business
associations in the surrounding
neighborhoods.
San francisco democratic party
as well as the residents
associations in the
neighborhoods.
I'm excited for this
legislation to take effect.
I'm for van ness to realize its
great potential as a thriving
commercial hub and for a new
grocery store to hopefully
restore food access to the
fillmore and surrounding
communities.
>> thank you colleagues and I
hope to have your support.
Thank you.
Supervisor sheryl I think we
can take this item same house,
same call.
>> without objection the
ordinance is passed on first
reading.
>> and MADAM Clerk, let's go to
roll call going to roll call
first member to introduce new
business.
>> supervisor chin thank you
person.
>> thank you, MADAM Clerk.
Colleagues.
Good afternoon again today
and it's really my honor to
introduce a resolution which
recognize MAY 10th as the
transcontinental chinese
railroad workers day.
>> for the contribution that
chinese workers make up make to
build this country's railroad
system under some of the most
dangerous and inhumane working
conditions.
>> laborers were required to
lay down rail, lay down rail
back tracks and other
infrastructure through
difficult two rings in the
sierra nevada and the rocky
mountains over 1000 to 100
chinese workers die from the
work accident avalanches
and explosions.
>> why the transcontinental
railroad?
It's highlighted in history
books.
The contribution of the chinese
workers are not often
acknowledged.
Chinese workers make up 80% of
the workforce for the central
railroad company.
Then governor of california,
leland stanford testified to
congress that chinese worker
chinese workers were
indispensable and a dangerous
working condition.
Discriminatory immigration
policies and social isolations.
>> chinese workers were
courageously took a stand to
organize for fair wages
and safer working conditions.
After years of hard work on one
of america's most marvelous
engineering feats a golden spot
marking the completion of the
transcontinental railroad on
MAY 10th, 1869.
The parliamentary summit utah.
However, the chinese-american
what did liberal e excluded
from this ceremony and were not
in any of the photographs which
commemorated the project
completion as this resolution
seeks to honor and recognize
the contribution and sacrifices
that the chinese worker made to
construct their country their
constant that the
transcontinental railroad
and the legacy of a vibrant
chinese-american community.
I want to appreciate the
chinese railroad workers
history center in san francisco
chinatown for their support for
this resolution.
>> there was also thank you.
Thank you.
Supervisor chen's supervisor
dorsey thank you, MADAM Clerk.
Colleagues, I am excited that
today together with mayor lurie
supervisors mahmood and sadr we
are introducing a resolution of
intent to create a commercial
to residential downtown
revitalization financing
district.
This local legislation will
help to implement bold and much
needed state legislation
authored by our own former
assembly member phil ting in ab
2488.
At a time when our city is
facing historic vacancy rates
and downtown when we're also on
the hook to facilitate the
production of 82,000 units of
housing by the end of our
housing element cycle we have a
golden opportunity to make real
progress on creating more
vibrant mixed use
neighborhoods.
Commercial to residential
conversions can be complicated
and expensive but they also
give us a unique opportunity to
improve upon many of the bad
land use decisions of the 20th
century to create 21st century
mixed use neighborhoods like
many of the neighborhoods I
represent which are blueprints
for economic vibrancy.
That's why I am committed to do
everything I can as a
policymaker to support
and incentivize these office to
residential conversion projects
with this legislation.
We're adding another tool to
the toolbox.
It will declare the city's
intent to create the downtown
revitalization and economic
recovery financing district
in which property tax increment
generated by commercial to
residential conversion projects
would be dispersed back to
those projects for up to 30
years as a financial incentive.
We're including the entirety of
downtown and market street the
whole market street corridor.
And I'm especially optimistic
about the opportunities these
projects will hold for the
mid-market neighborhood.
>> once this legislation passes
we'll get to work on the
formation of the required
district board that will adopt
procedures and regular
regulations for this opt
in program.
I want to thank mayor lurie for
his leadership on this issue.
Staff at the office of economic
and workforce development for
their work.
Supervisors mahmud and sadr
and their teams.
And the down my downtown
colleagues and their
and everybody there for their
work and support on this I look
forward to being a part of
these efforts to revitalize our
downtown core.
>> and the rest I submit thank
you.
>> supervisor dorsey supervisor
and gaudio submit.
Thank you.
Supervisor fielder submit.
Supervisor mahmood submit.
Thank you.
Supervisor randleman well, I do
have an introduction.
>> breaking the chain.
Sorry everybody.
Today on this earth day I'm
introducing a resolution
recognizing APRIL 2025 as earth
month.
>> the first first earth day
was celebrated in APRIL of
1970.
The brainchild of then senator
nelson of wisconsin.
The first earth day saw 20
million americans take to the
streets to demonstrate against
climate change, climate change
and paved the way for
establishment of the
environmental protection agency
and passage of the clean air
act, clean water act and other
significant environmental
legislation.
Since then of course the
severity of the climate crisis
has only grown.
Each year millions of people
around the world are killed,
harmed or displaced by climate
emergencies that include
wildfires, tropical storms,
flash floods, mudslides and sea
level rise.
And 2024 was the first year
in which global average
temperatures exceeded 1.5
c.
The internationally recognized
threshold for global warming
identified in the 2015 paris
agreement as the point beyond
which more severe
and potentially irreversible
environmental consequences
could be expected.
This APRIL we celebrate earth
month in recognition of the
environmental progress that has
been made since the first earth
day but also the growing
urgency and scale of ongoing
environmental harm to the
planet.
I want to thank almost all the
members of the board for your
co-sponsorship.
I also want to thank the
department of environment for
their work year round to focus
the city on on environmental
sustainability.
And I want to thank calvin
particularly the work they've
done they've done around
climate week.
And then I want to thank calvin
howe in my office for his work
on the resolution and the rest
I submit.
>> thank you MR. PRESIDENT.
Supervisor miller submit thank
you.
Supervisor sartor submit.
Thank you.
Supervisors cheryl submit.
>> thank you.
Supervisor walton thank you,
MADAM Chair.
I mean MADAM Clerk.
Colleagues today along with
supervisors and guardiola
fielder chan and melgar I'm
introducing the entitlement
package for the prologis
proposal at 749 toland street
and bellevue's market zone
neighborhood a place that's
long powered san francisco
through essential industry
and labor but that has also
endured decades of
disinvestment.
This proposal marks a milestone
moment for our district.
It includes two new state of
the art industrial buildings
totaling over 2,000,000ft2 of
flexible space to support
logistics, local makers
and light manufacturing design
with the future in mind.
the project features solar
power, rainwater reuse and a
strong commitment to achieving
zero carbon certificate ation.
Prologis is also investing
directly into the neighborhood
rebuilding eight blocks of
public streets to city
standards a $50 million
infrastructure upgrade.
On top of that they're
committing $8 million in direct
community contributions and 11
million more dollars in market
zone improvements including
support for the produce markets
reinvestment plan and small
businesses development along
third street.
This project will generate
nearly 800 construction jobs
annually and create close to
2000 permanent on site jobs.
It also is the first
development agreement on a
private project in the city to
include a micro lego with
dedicated opportunities for
hyperlocal bayview contractors.
And it comes with first source
hiring agreement to prioritize
local residents for both
construction and long term
jobs.
This is one of the largest
private investments in bayview
in decades.
But more than that it is a
model for what community driven
equity focused
and environmentally responsible
development should look like.
The light industrial businesses
in this area like food
distribution and water
treatment keep our city
running.
This project strengthens those
systems while uplifting the
people who live and work here.
we look forward to continued
collaboration with prologis
and community partners to bring
this project to life and to
help bayview lead the way
in san francisco's equitable
growth.
I want to thank community
members and labor partners who
served on the gateway advisory
committee.
Your input helped shape the
package that reflects
bellevue's values
and priorities.
I also would like to thank john
lao and topia and susan ma from
the office of economic
and workforce development.
The team at prologis the market
zone rudy gonzales and the
building trades and my
legislative aide percy birch
for all of their work to get us
here today.
I also have an in memoriam for
otis winfield affectionately
known as overtime, a beloved
son of the bayview community
whose presence brought joy,
warmth and unmistakable energy
to all who knew him.
Born in alexandria, louisiana
and raised in san francisco
from the age of one, otis made
the city his lifelong home,
shaping it with his vibrant
personality, a strong work
ethic and deep love for family.
A proud graduate of woodrow
wilson high school, otis was
known in his youth for his
passion for basketball, music,
dancing and his signature love
for a good meal.
His voice his smile and his
infectious laughter wear a
constant source of light
and joy.
He built a long and respected
career in construction
and public service working with
at&t and the department of
public works.
Always known for his
reliability and dedication,
otis has faith in GOD was
central to his life as was his
devotion to those he loved.
He was a kind hearted, funny
and spirited man whose
strength, loyalty
and compassion defined him.
His legacy lives on in the
lives he touched, the laughter
he sparked and the love he gave
so freely.
Otis winfield junior was called
home on APRIL 8th, 2025.
His memory will forever remain
in the heart of san francisco
and in the souls of all who
were fortunate enough to share
in his journey.
>> the rest I submit.
Thank you, supervisor walton.
And last but not least
supervisor chan submit submit.
Thank you very much, MR.
PRESIDENT.
>> let's go to our 230 special
order the special order at 230
is the recognition of
commendations for meritorious
service to the city and county
of san francisco.
>> we will start with district
five supervisor mahmud.
>> thank you, colleagues.
I am supposed to going to put
this on my head because the
person we're honoring grace.
>> do you want to come up with
your friends and all the
japantown folks feel free to
come up as well and support.
>> so to colleagues today I am
happy today to be honoring
grace mercury, the executive
director of the japantown
community benefit district
and the neon mochi street fair
.
On sunday I walked in the
northern california cherry
blossom parade and when I got
to japantown I saw grace in her
and her office and waved.
And I think that's a big
representation of who grace is.
>> a lot of what's happened
in japantown over last couple
of years has been an result of
her efforts.
Yet still she takes a back seat
and works in the background
and never takes the front seat
and takes credit for things.
Today we wanted to honor her
for all her work in public
because she's not only while
she wasn't on the official
stage and she was invited to be
a guest, she instead again
speaks to her humility and how
humble she is.
To even not be the star of the
show is what responsible for
making japantown great.
>> japantown was buzzing with
life over the weekend with the
festival because it's a
neighborhood that's always
buzzing sales tax revenue was
up last spring by 17% compared
to pre-covid numbers even
though there are renovations of
the peace plaza.
Restaurants and stores are busy
.
>> what's the secret sauce to
town that makes it so
successful?
It's impossible to tell the
story of japantown success as a
result without talking about
grace her work on the cbd, the
neon mochi street fair are
beyond a part of what makes
japantown not just a global
destination but a neighborhood
with a big heart and a close
knit intergenerational fabric.
She's not only a leader but a
mentor.
In fact, one of her mentees
described how deeply meaningful
it is to see grace being
recognized not just for her
impact but for her generosity
of spirit.
Grace has become well-known
citywide for her ability to
bring people together artists,
merchants, youth and neighbors
in a way that's rare and deeply
rooted in community care.
>> she's an alum of morning
star school in washington high
school.
She's committed to the
community and shows that it
runs deep.
>> she was a day camp
participant at jcc becoming a
counselor as she got older.
In 1997 she took over the neon
marching street fair, an annual
event celebrating japan town's
art and culture.
It's such an impressive
undertaking coordinating
vendors and volunteers to put
on an event that draws tens of
thousands from across the
region and it's since expanded
to a series of pop ups which I
think unique to many of the
street fairs across the city.
Each pop up has always been
sponsored by a nonprofit so all
the money that is generated
from these nonprofit from these
street fairs for the food goes
to the nonprofit.
I know at the festival on
sunday I ate the terry burger
teriyaki burger from the
firefighters which went to
kimchi and I got some popcorn
that went to rosa parks
elementary.
So I think again it speaks to
the character of how you
thought and the community's
thought about how even those
small businesses should be
benefiting the nonprofits that
are the heart of the district.
>> grace has also ensured that
neon marches street fair is
first and foremost about
strengthening and lifting up
community including partnering
closely with these nonprofits
and cultural organizations
and focusing on youth
mentorship creating a new
generation of grace's to
continue to grace our presence
with the tradition of the
community.
>> and if that wasn't enough
grace took on the mantle of the
executive director of the
japantown cbd shortly after it
came into existence in 2017.
She hit the ground running
making japantown cbd an
absolute force and supporting
businesses in the area.
Grace along with the deputy
director brandon quan and two
ambassadors alan yuki who are
behind her as well helped keep
the community safe and clean
through trash cans and cameras.
They also raise over $500,000
to support small businesses
in the area during covid.
Connecting businesses with
grant opportunities many of
which told me how much your
work on doing language access
for these businesses
and helping them access the
grants in the city that they
otherwise would not have known
was only possible because of
you and the cbd's effort
in making sure they were able
to survive during the pandemic.
>> it's her unique leadership
chip and artistry is seen
across japantown.
She has lent her graphic design
talent.
I didn't know that to projects
like the japantown history walk
and the japantown fan under the
webster street bed bridge.
Both are vivid cultural
landmarks in our city.
She also designed the logos for
jaycee wiki and the cbd itself
and beyond the visuals, her
cheerful demeanor and can do
attitude have strengthened the
relationship between businesses
residents in the city.
As a personal anime fan.
I appreciate all you do to
raise awareness for different
anime opportunities.
I know you had a person
responsible for innovative
partnership like a lord of the
rings anime partnership with
the cbd and the posters were
all over and brought
sponsorship and business to the
community.
So thinking thank you for
allowing me to continue to nerd
out every time I come to
japantown.
I know supervisor cheryl and I
did a merchant walk earlier
this year in japantown and even
when traveling with electeds
everyone we talked to really
just wanted to meet you because
your boundless energy paired
with lifelong community
connections has made you the
perfect example of what a
neighborhood leader should be
like.
>> so colleagues, please join
me in commending grace harakiri
on her immense impact
in japantown and san francisco
and I hope to see all of you
this weekend at the pop up at
the neon MARCH street fair
in AUGUST as well as beyond
grateful and of course our
district supervisor mahmud, you
know you're a godsend.
>> so thank you.
It's an honor to receive this
recognition.
But like I always said, it
takes a village and behind me
is the village that keeps me
moving forward too.
>> so I got to give a head to
all these folks behind me.
>> jay town is my home town.
I breathe and live jay town so
I'm going to keep on doing
whatever I can to keep
japantown surviving
and thriving.
>> so again, thank you all so
much.
I don't know who fed you all
this information but I was
thinking oh my GOD.
But thank you.
>> what an honor and thank you
all from japantown.
Thank you very much
.
>> next up we have district six
supervisor matt dorsey.
>> thank you PRESIDENT
Randleman colleagues on the
occasion of their transfer to
hawaii it is my distinct honor
to recognize major's darren
and mary norton of the
salvation army.
>> could you please take it?
Thank and I do so as an
expression of gratitude for
their extraordinary leadership,
compassion and unwavering
service to the people of san
francisco.
now the salvation army offers
charitable services worldwide,
of course, but their work on
the west coast began this
organization's work on the west
coast began in 1883 right here
in san francisco.
And for many decades up to
and including today the south
of market neighborhood I
represent has proudly claimed
as its own the salvation army's
headquarters and many of its
marquee services including the
harbor light drug treatment
center since majors darren
and mary norton arrived here
in 2019, they have been at the
forefront of addressing some of
our city's most pressing
challenges homelessness,
addiction and poverty.
Through their initiative the
way out they have provided a
lifeline to countless
individuals offering immediate
access to drug treatment
and recovery services
transitional housing and long
term support.
Their holistic approach has
transformed lives including the
lives of many I've come to know
as friends and fellow members
of the recovery community.
But even more than that they've
set a standard for
compassionate care in our
community beyond their
professional commitments, the
nortons have demonstrated at a
heartfelt personal dedication
to those in need whether it's
delivering thousands of meals
to homebound seniors during the
holidays or responding to
emergencies and homeless
encampments.
They embody the true spirit of
service and in fact
distributing meals from their
soma service center on
thanksgiving morning has become
a holiday tradition for me that
I'm always grateful to be
joined by board PRESIDENT
Rafael mandel and at the
nortons work has provided
comfort and hope to many
reinforcing the values of
empathy and community that are
so foundational to the city of
saint francis majors, darren
and mary norton.
Your tireless efforts
and compassionate leadership
leave an enduring legacy for
san francisco and countless
lives that you have helped to
change and helped to save.
On behalf of the board of
supervisors and a grateful city
on behalf of a grateful
recovery community and many of
the members who are here today,
thank you for your service
and please accept our fondest
wishes to both of you for your
next chapter in hawaii.
Congratulations.
>> supervisor dorsey thank you
so much.
Present management fellow
supervisors we are so honored
and grateful to just receive
this commendation today.
Mary and I gave our lives to
GOD many years ago to serve him
wherever he takes us and to be
a part of the great work the
salvation army does.
We serve in jesus name to serve
those without discrimination
and help make a difference
and we've just been so thrilled
and honored to serve here
in san francisco and help make
a difference in the lives of
others.
And we've shared quite often
mary and I that when we arrived
in 2018 the salvation army
seemed to be swimming upstream
as it related to offering
treatment and recovery.
And we've seen in the last 5 or
6 years just a tremendous sway
of support to come alongside us
to offer expand the solutions
space for people that need
treatment and recovery in a way
out.
And so we're so honored to be a
part of this effort and to help
san franciscans get off the
streets find hope through
recovery and put them on to a
better life.
And thank you for all of your
support and your terrific words
of encouragement today.
>> so thank you so very, very
much here for this.
>> district seven supervisor
M.L. Ga.
Thank you PRESIDENT Mandell
and if I could please ask
priestesses is stacy board
jennifer mantel, katie ketchum
,katherine wagner and pastor
tom longino to come up please.
>> thank you.
Okay and thank you PRESIDENT
Man and colleagues today I am
honoring her church
and emerging liberating
feminist congregation in the
christian lutheran denomination
as they are a vital part of
district seven spiritual
community.
>> if you ever have driven down
portola near twin peaks
and admired a gloriously purple
building that brightens any
foggy day that is the home of
her church, I want to give a
warm welcome to the staff here
in the midst of this very
troubled world at her church is
an oasis of joy, comfort
renewal.
It is a place where women
and people of every gender
expression are honored as
sacred beings with music,
sacred stories, imagery
and humor.
They celebrate the ancient
and ever present mother
and find renewal in her
blessing.
They honor the earth in a
cosmic body that supports us
especially through multiple
engagement of the arts which is
especially important today
in the times we're living
in and on this earth day today
her church's commitment to
seeking divinity in the arts
and creative expression can be
seen right away from its
distinctive colorful and joyful
purple exterior through their
celebration of diversity,
artistic expression and the
divine feminine.
Her church has deeply enriched
the lives of its congregation
as a unique spiritual hub their
embodiment of the values of
compassion, creativity,
inclusivity has left an
everlasting legacy of
acceptance and joy throughout
our city in our region
and district seven
in particular.
>> so thank you her church for
building this community for
making a better world a happy
earth day.
Happy birthday to you all.
And now I would like to invite
princess stacy board to share a
few words.
>> thank you on behalf of many
,many, many people who have
come through our doors.
sometimes they don't stay.
>> sometimes they do.
We are grateful for your
recognition.
We wanted to remind you all why
we are purple.
>> in 2008 when san francisco
was bold enough to say
and bring about the whole state
of california to recognize gay
marriages purple was the color
that represents that purple is
also the color for the ancient
goddess that is the mother who
has been around for 300,000
years traveling with her
creatures and human beings.
And also purple is the color of
justice.
And we are grateful that we
live in san francisco and here
we know that it's filled with
politicians and lovers of
justice of all stripes.
And so we are grateful to be a
part of this city and a part of
your where you are our
superintendent.
>> you might not know this but
at our building if you walk
around and try and take some
pictures of all our beautiful
art you should come.
>> we have hundreds of pieces
of beautiful art there many
done by our community members.
>> but if you write one part of
the building and you take your
picture and your phone will say
for sale extension if you're at
another part of the building
and you take a picture it will
say twin peaks and in another
part of the building if you
take a picture it will say mira
loma.
>> so we're almost all of your
district by the way, as well as
representatives of people from
all over.
>> and so we are grateful we
brought you a couple little
gifts because you need more
purple as a reminder of your
great justice work here in san
francisco and in all of you.
>> so thank you very much.
>> oh wait, we had.
Oh, we had one more thing
and because it's earth day we
can't hardly but let me just.
>> you already said this is
tom.
He's our our our adjunct pastor
and they all have all kinds of
roles.
Katy ketchum is priestess of
music and painting.
And jennifer is our priestess
of tactile spirituality
and healing arts.
And katherine, you always need
a priestess of the treasury
right.
As well as hospitality.
But it is earth day.
So we wanted to remind you
there is a woman and she will
rise for you is a woman and she
will rise.
We will live in her we will
live in her.
>> the earth is a woman and she
will rise.
The earth is a woman and she
will rise we will live in we
will live in her and you can
all do it.
The earth is a movement and she
will rise it is a movement
and she will rise.
>> we will be heard.
>> we will live in her way.
Thank you.
Okay to take a picture.
All right.
Last but not least for district
eight I'm going to invite
franco stevens I think to go to
that mike.
There we go.
I think we're getting set up
perfect.
Okay, colleagues in recognition
of lesbian visibility week it
is my great honor to present a
special commendation to franco
stevens.
Franco's a maryland native but
moved to san francisco when she
was 18.
And like lots of other young
arriving in san francisco
in the late 80s and early 90s,
she found her way to a
different light bookstore on
castro street looking for
community.
Now specifically she was
looking to find lesbian focused
magazines but at the time there
just wasn't much.
She took a job at different
light a thing I didn't know
until we started working on
this commendation.
And in 1990 franco and a team
of volunteers launched deneuve.
>> at the time advertisers were
not convinced that the lesbian
market was viable so franco had
to fund the magazine with her
own savings and winnings from
betting at the racetrack.
>> within two years though
she'd been able to secure
advertising from corporations
like budweiser and warner
brothers.
She built her subscriber base
by partnering with naiad press,
the largest feminist publisher
in the world and making tv
appearances on cnn.
>> and harold over riviera.
>> in 1996, the magazine's
changed its name to curve
franco's journey as chronicled
in the 2020 documentary ahead
of the curve, co-directed by
her wife jan raanan.
The film explores franco's
impact on lesbian media and the
ongoing fight for inclusivity
and representation in the lgbtq
community and her journey to
create the curve foundation.
She officially launched the
foundation in 2021 to empower
lesbians women trans women
and non-binary people through
intergenerational programing
and community building.
>> franco has served on the
boards of glad and the san
francisco lgbt center.
>> she's received numerous
awards and honors including the
globe historical society,
historical society history
makers award and she's entered
the hall of fame for the
association of lgbtq plus
journalists.
>> for the last few years my
office has been able to work
with franco and city hall
building management to light up
this building for lesbian
visibility day this year.
>> franco decided we should go
bigger and it has been a
delight for my legislative aide
on her and I to work with her
and lex rosenberg from the
career foundation and rebecca
roth from the lgbt center who
is here.
Thank you, rebecca.
On that project this year san
francisco has been and will
continue celebrating lesbian
visibility week from APRIL 21st
through the 27th.
There are events across the
city including a flag raising
and reception on the mayor's
balcony this thursday and to
which I hope all of you will
come.
And unveiling of the living
lesbian legends mural on friday
in the castro and the lighting
of city hall for the closing of
lesbian visibility week this
sunday evening.
>> franco we love you and the
floor is yours.
>> thank you so much.
And PRESIDENT Thank you for all
the support you've shown to me
and the community over the past
however long.
>> I just want to say that
celebrating lesbian visibility
week is a privilege being able
to activate our community to
come together with lgbtq plus
women, non-binary people
and have them all lifted up
together is a dream that 19
year old me coming to san
francisco not having known
another person woman even
existed I didn't even know the
word lesbian to coming full
circle to be recognized with
you here today is omg it's
surreal and through lesbian
visibility week I think we can
unite the community in this
time where it is dangerous to
be a person.
You know we need to embrace our
trans siblings as part of our
community and part of the
reason why lesbian visibility
week was started in the first
place is because there started
to be this connotation that
lesbians were not inclusive of
trans people which is
completely not the case as a
few people out there that are
not supportive of the trans
community curve stands very
clear in its mission that we
are inclusive of the trans
community of non-binary people
of everyone under the lgbtq
plus women's community and it's
because of our allies like you
that we feel seen and supported
.
>> when I first started working
at that bookstore I just wanted
to meet another lesbian
somebody who identified the
same way as I did.
>> there was one other lesbian
that worked there and it was
mostly gay men and I felt like
those gay men lifted me up
and it was a time in the early
90s that you know, we were
faced with the aids epidemic
and my friends were taking care
of all their gay brothers
and I've always felt this very
kinship between the whole
community and and that we need
to stand behind each other
and not think of it as like a
little piece of the pie that
you know, if gay men get one
thing lesbians can't have
another thing.
>> and being recognized today I
didn't do it by myself.
Yeah, maybe I had the idea to
start a magazine and I did some
crazy things like oh betting
all my money on a horse race to
see if it could come to
fruition.
>> but it's the people behind
the magazine for all these
years and the women in the
community that have made my
work possible.
I'd like to give hats off to my
wife and co-founder of the
curve foundation jen ronan
tilex and sharon who have been
along for a ride for a while
and of course rebecca for your
partnership and lesbian
visibility and taking it to the
next level and to my community
you bouie me, you are the
strength that I see and what
propels me to do this work.
I see you I want to honor you.
It's a privilege.
Rafael.
>> you're the bomb.
I think you're the greatest.
So thank you for for making
this possible.
>> and on behalf of all the
women in this city, let's go.
Okay.
You want to, right?
Yeah.
We can have all everybody.
Wherever there
.
All right, so I think MADAM
Clerk that takes us to public
comment.
>> yes.
All right, let's do it at this
time the board welcomes your
public comment.
Please line up on your right
hand side of the chamber.
You MAY speak to the approval
of the meeting minutes other
general matters not on today's
agenda but must be within the
board's subject matter
jurisdiction.
All other content has been
reported out to the board by an
act by a committee where the
public comment requirement has
occurred.
We are setting the timer for
two minutes.
Please make sure you utilize
the full two minutes before you
leave the podium if that is
your intention.
Let's welcome our first
speaker.
Welcome.
Welcome sir.
>> I want you to hello.
Good afternoon, supervisors.
My name is henry janov.
I am here on behalf of the
armenian national committee of
america.
I'm also a san francisco native
.
>> almost 110 years ago today
the ottoman empire set out to
erase the armenian nation from
the face of the earth.
1.5 million innocent men, women
and children met their end
in some of the most brutal ways
imaginable today the same pan
turkish ideology that fueled
the 1915 genocide has returned
with renewed force.
In 2023 the azerbaijani regime
led by dictator ilham aliyev
with turkish support launched a
brutal military assault on the
armenian population of artsakh
days before the assault that
dictator ilham announced quote
we will drive the armenians out
like dogs.
The same dictator who years
prior to the assault stated
in an address to his youth the
armenians of the world are our
enemies.
>> the genocidal intent
in these statements is clear.
Statements like these helped
motivate hate crimes against
our community all over the
world including the worst
attacks right here in san
francisco.
With the complete destruction
of the armenian cultural center
and the heinous attacks against
the only armenian school
in northern california kayseri
the perpetrators have yet to be
caught and the community as of
yet has been unable to rebuild.
>> history has taught us that
what happens when such
genocidal warnings are ignored
are forgotten and international
community not holding them
accountable only serves to
embolden these regimes to
undertake efforts to quote
finish their grandparents
mission as stated by turkish
PRESIDENT Recep tayyip erdogan
.
We are very thankful to
supervisor melgar and this
entire board of supervisors
in the city of san francisco
for voting on the armenian
genocide commemoration day
resolution today on behalf of
the armenian national committee
of america, san francisco.
Thank you.
Thank you for your comments.
>> welcome, MISS Brown.
MR. Ahmed.
MR. Rahman no, no applause
during general public comment.
Thank you, sir.
MISS Browni like to you over
here.
I'm here to talk about my son
as well is every time I come
here we talk about unsolved
homicides.
I come here because my son was
murdered AUGUST 14th, 2006.
To this day his cases unsolved
.
He was shot with a
semiautomatic gun on his own
saving someone else's life.
To this day I am requesting you
know I bring all the other
homicide victims pictures with
me all the time.
>> my quest is for unsolved
homicides and to this day I'm
just still waiting for other
ways to pay tipsters to come
forth.
There's supposed to be a
resolution coming up and I'm
still waiting for that.
As a mother who lost her child,
my son's birthday was APRIL 6th
this month.
So I'm I'm feeling some type of
way.
I go to the police commission
every wednesday.
There's no police commission
this wednesday.
>> so I'm here today.
>> mayor gavin newsom, former
mayor gavin newsom said I know
who killed her child.
Her child the police know who
killed a dna, know who killed
her.
>> but no one wants to come
forth because of retaliation.
>> I bring this other picture
of me standing over my son
before the funeral happened.
>> I bring this other picture
of what the perpetrators left
me a lifeless body of a
beautiful, handsome boy that
was murdered.
He was my only son and I want
justice.
>> so I'm hoping the board of
supervisors passed that
resolution on how to pay
tipsters some kind of money to
solve these cases, these
unsolved cases.
>> I need help.
We need help as mothers.
>> thank you.
Thank you, MRS. Brown.
>> just just for the audience.
>> just sir, please hold your
applause.
There is a rule approved by the
board that there are no audible
sounds of support or if you're
against an item if you'd like
to make some statement, please
just signal as such.
>> welcome to our next speaker.
>> hi.
Thank you.
Welcome.
Hi.
Board of supervisors.
Good afternoon.
My name is charlene brown
and I've been a holmbridge care
provider for two and a half
years.
I'm also a member of seiu tv's
bargaining team for home bridge
caregivers.
>> I'm here today to speak
in support of additional
funding for the home bridge
program and tell you about the
important services we provide.
>> the work we do I believe
keeps our community safe.
>> I genuinely believe that
caregivers go hand-in-hand with
the city to help bring the city
to a better state of of mind us
a better state for the
community.
I just truly believe that
caregivers go hand in hand with
police officers.
We go hand-in-hand with fire
departments because we are the
first ones on the scene to make
sure that these clients that
we're taking all over the city
are well.
I believe we go hand in hand
with taking the care of the
mental capacity of the clients
and just doing daily living
activities trying to keep these
people who are in homes that
are like 60 plus.
>> just trying to keep them
independent living and also
in a healthy environment.
>> home bridge needs additional
funding to keep me and my
coworkers safe on the job.
I was actually assaulted in the
tenderloin area JULY of 2024.
i was assaulted helping taking
care of the clients and we're
often working in places that
have pests and other health
hazards.
>> we go into communities we
sometimes aren't familiar with
and that puts us at risk.
>> we need time for the
community too.
>> we need the funding for the
community to basically like
give us safety more safety
classes, more safety training
and as home bridge providers.
>> we just don't make enough to
to have a livable wage.
>> we don't make enough for
livable wages to start
in reverse studio right now is
2200 a month which is way too
much to afford the current
wages we have.
Our program needs additional
funding and workers need a
highway so we can continue
serving our community members
and keeping our bay.
>> thank you for your comments
and for all the service that
you provide.
>> thank you.
Thank you.
Let's hear from our next
speaker please.
>> hi, how are you?
Hi.
My name's jensen xencor.
I have been holmbridge home
care provider for 13 years.
>> I'm here to speak because I
support of the home bridge
program and tell you about
important service we provide.
>> in 13 years we house
hundreds of san francisco
residents who are at risk of
not receiving care later but
send off my crying.
>> have a mental illness.
>> home care workers bridge
gaps in san francisco's long
term care system.
We care for the people who do
not have access to the the
other resources.
The work we do is not easy.
>> many of us struggle to weave
sheraton towers because there
is a lack of the training.
>> new hires often leave after
a couple months because of how
challenging the job can be.
I myself wanted to give up a
couple time but now I still
stay because I care about my
coworkers.
>> I care about my clients but
without higher wages or better
training caregivers will
continue to leave in this
industry.
>> most though are those most
in the in need such as people
we've come as a mental health
issue.
>> we will not get the quality
care.
>> thank you.
Thank you for your comments.
Sorry to late.
>> welcome to our next speaker
.
>> greetings.
My name is malick's enough
room.
I'm here on behalf of the alice
griffith community
and unfortunately it is not
good news.
I first want to start off by
thanking supervisor shimon
walton for doing an amazing job
on his meeting APRIL 7th which
was my birthday.
I could not be there.
Normally I'm always there but
in this right we are back for
another one on this one here
where we have experienced some
really interesting event
yesterday where a ceiling has
fell in on an elder during an
event.
We had an art exhibition with
the youth and the ceiling fell
in on the elder along with the
with a water draft from a long
time leaking pipe that had
never been dealt with was
happening and alice griffith is
not an isolated event and it is
really painstaking to have to
come all the way down here to
express this because we know
that the city knows this
and right now we're under the
condition of the great swindle
is what I like to call it
in the sense that we are right
now in the position of trying
to figure out how are we going
to be able to live in a place
like this where not only are
ceilings falling we have
growing infested oceans that
are developing and we also have
issues with with the elevators
.
I was going to say evictions I
mean I mean it just goes on
and on and sewage everything.
So we have a series of issues
that happened initially had
another development we lived
in it was much better.
They have something that looks
better but it is not better.
>> do you want to say
something?
Yes sir.
If you could finish your two
minutes before the next two
minutes.
>> so I just want to make sure
that no one that the city
boards or thank you, sir.
Thank you for your comments.
>> great.
Thank you.
oh, there is a timer on the
podium if you could watch that
timer next time for that to fit
your comments into that time
period.
Thank you.
>> welcome to our next speaker
.
>> all right.
Okay.
My name is micah pinkston.
I'm a resident of bayview
apartments in hunters point.
>> I'm here with the city wide
alliance which is all of us
here standing together.
>> we first we want to thank
supervisor watson for holding a
hearing on APRIL 7th to shine a
light on the horrible
conditions that are our
neighbors at alice griffin are
facing right now here today.
I was actually a witness to
what took place yesterday
and that was horrible.
It actually really scared me
half to death but I was able to
stand tall and make sure the
senior got the assistance that
she needed.
>> what is happening at aba's
griffin is not an isolated
incident.
Similar issues are happening
all across heard communities
in san francisco and the
related properties in hunter's
point.
We've been we're being we've
been dealing with low quality
renovations that use cheap
substandard materials.
Contractors are often nonunion
and unqualified and the work
being done doesn't meet the
needs of our community.
We we deserve better.
Security on site has become
abusive.
people's cars are being towed
without warning and there's no
professionalism, no transparent
seeing and no one no one
resident can actually talk to.
This is not how you treat a
community.
We're also deeply concerned
about displacement as
renovations are taking place
and moving forward.
>> many of us fear being pushed
out of our homes without real.
>> without any support and able
to return.
>> we've seen this happen
before in our neighborhoods
and we don't want history to
repeat itself.
Mayor lurie we x we're asking
that you come in to the hunters
point, walk through the
community with us and hear
directly from the people living
with these conditions.
We need leadership that shows
up follows through with
accountability and oversight.
>> thank.
Thank you for your comments.
All right.
Let's hear from our next
speaker.
Welcome.
>> welcome.
Good afternoon, supervisors.
My name is MR. Dennis williams
of d5.
I'm a microbiologist a
developer also a board of
supervisor awarded leader
and I'm here today as part of
the S.F. Hyper local building
trades collective.
I want to first thank all the
new supervisors I haven't had a
chance to address you guys.
I want to thank supervisor
filner who we worked in during
covid during our senate
campaign and it was excellent.
She's very diligent about all
ethnic groups.
So I want to say thank you.
First of all, I want to thank
supervisor sherman walton for
holding this hearing APRIL 7th
to shine a light on the
horrible conditions that our
neighbors in alice griffin are
forced to live with but is not
isolated to alice griffin right
plaza east related properties
millennium.
So forth and so on are facing
similar issues and have
uninhabitable by west point
and so forth.
I'm here today also to speak on
the lack of section three
employment opportunities at
plaza e's, alice griffith
and even the new developments
in the bipoc communities at
large.
They've claimed repairs are
underway at a lot of these
places but yet no residents
have been hired unfortunately
and recently they announced a
single job at plaza east which
has over 160 residents.
One job is not a good movement
to the community as you guys
know is really an insult and we
are skilled labor is in our
community.
Developers gcs and others
truckers we deserve inclusion
not racial discrimination.
I demand mayor lurie to come
in and to come and lend his
time as he does in mission bay
and other areas to the bipoc
communities specifically alice
griffin who on the outside the
landscaping is beautiful but
when you open the front doors
you see deplorable conditions
that says something about the
general contractors and the
management companies as well as
the developer.
Mccormick at variance salazar I
just want to thank again
supervisor walton and there you
guys for listening to us
and every here because I stand
with the thank you for your
comments welcome to our next
speaker.
Good afternoon my name is
kelvin sitting I live in plaza
east and serve on the council
on tenant council.
I am here with the city wide
hud alliance.
We want to thank supervisors
shumlin walton for holding a
hearing on APRIL 7th the to
shine a light on the horrible
conditions that our neighbors
are alex griffins are forced to
live with what hap what is
happening at alice griffin is
not and so incident similar
issues are happening all across
hud communities in san
francisco our homes at plaza
ice are in bad shape.
Many units have mot leaks
broken floors and rodents.
This ain't small issues there
are serious and have gone on
for too long.
We keep hearing promises but we
don't see results.
Our repairs are moving too
slowly and families are left
waiting.
We also need the housing
authorities to sign the letter
of insurance the okay so that
our rights and protections are
in in writing this document
comes from us the residents
and it should be taken
seriously.
>> thank you, sir.
Thank you for your comments.
>> welcome to our next speaker
.
Good afternoon.
My name is martha hollins and I
am the resident counsel of
plaza ice.
We are the tenants association
and I'm here today to talk on
some of the things that was
just said here in plaza ice.
I want to thank you all for
having us here today first of
all and what's happening for
over two years.
29 units set vacant in plaza
ice and there are still many,
many of our units that are
occupied and unoccupied that
need terrible knee repair very
badly.
Most of them some of them are
from our seniors.
Our seniors are living in in
in their units with mold.
They're a pestilence.
There are all kinds of
conditions that need to be
fixed floors are falling
in why?
Okay.
Why do we live with floors
and rules falling?
We have already had well
mccormick and bearing to come
up from st louis and this was
in 1986 1989 to do repairs on
the new buildings that had been
built.
But now you know those
buildings are falling apart.
Okay.
And you know, no one is there
to you know, repair they do
repairs.
Yeah.
But those repairs are somewhat
band-aids.
You can call them band-aids
because they have been
band-aids put on those repairs
every since the buildings.
The new building 193 units have
been put up and we are kind of
tired because they're getting
ready to do something to it
again, I guess refurbishing it.
>> okay.
So they're going to refurbish
it.
>> yeah.
Thank you.
Thank you for your comments.
Welcome to our next speaker.
>> thank you to the board of
supervisors.
My name is rene cyprian and I
live at the frederick douglass
haynes garden apartments in the
fillmore and I am here with
citywide but the citywide hud
allowance I'm speaking today
because our community is in a
crisis.
You have heard from the
speakers of what's going
in bayview hunters point but
I'm here to speak on another
issue today I live in frederick
douglass st.
I am a native san francisco
siskin.
I grew up in the fillmore
and today I ask you to remember
the fillmore if you don't know
what the full moon was like I
ask that you go to your
archives and find out what the
what the fillmore was.
>> it was a black enclave
currently I'm seeing that we're
facing accelerated displacement
of black families who have
lived here for generations the
outmigration of black residents
is not by chance.
>> it's a result of
longstanding neglect and failed
housing policies our
communities deserve better.
>> the same goes for bayview
hunters point.
>> I would also ask you to look
in the archives and see the
black community in the bay
buchanan point what we are
seeing our neighbors who are
undergoing rapid demographic
shifts with no policies
in place to protect legacy
residents.
>> if you look around you can
see how quickly the makeup of
our community is changing
and yet there are no safeguards
to ensure that black families
who built these neighborhoods
can stay on top of that there
is no pathway for return for
the black san franciscans who
wish to return to our beautiful
city.
This must change.
I'm also asking our mayor to
confirm his attendance for a
walk through in our public.
>> thank you for your comments.
If any of you would like to
submit your comments we could
certainly include them in the
minutes.
>> um let's hear from our next
speaker.
Welcome.
>> hi.
I'm a little nervous.
Sorry.
Thanks for having us here.
I'm a fellow I'm speaking on
behalf of frederick douglas
haynes as a resident.
My name is danish ackerman
and I just really want more
oversight over the trash in our
apartment complex.
>> I literally stay on the
second floor right above the
trash can and it gets packed up
daily.
We also have someone who
trespasses into our apartments
and she goes to the trash
in the security kicks her out.
Just the other day she put her
pants down in bubbled in.
>> the kids are playing outside
so we really need oversight
over the trash kids.
>> thank you for your comments
.
My name is salah aka chandler
and I'm an abolition ism, a
social justice fighter for my
people, for my nation.
And I'm truly thankful that my
people are standing today to
deal with these issues because
it's been going on for many,
many years.
>> the bottom line myself have
came here concerning being
called in by hollows in bayview
hunters point concerning three
arson fires that took place
in bayview even though it was a
couple of years ago I went to
the fbi of san francisco
and asked them to investigate.
I went to the recent district
attorney office and asked them
to investigate the fires.
Inspectors was supposed to
investigate.
>> I have witnesses three
consecutive arsons of mothers
and grandmothers and children
are in these buildings and no
one till this day has not given
us the answer to the three
arson fires that took place
in bayview.
Hunters point.
>> I think it's very
unfortunate that you would
think that a riot has to take
place.
To speak in regards solution is
that the new mayor and also the
represented to have needs to
call in for the particular
management that manage these
units that's given to the city.
It needs to be a freeze.
They should not be paid.
They should not be paid until
we deal with the issues that's
happening within the
disenfranchized community.
>> we hear of all the other
cultures banned acknowledge for
they aren't their culture
and their genders but yet ours
is being destroyed.
The purpose is to de power us
you think?
>> but as much as you try to de
power us we're going to rise
and take our position that's
rightfully ours and we're not
going to do it in anger
and we're not going to do it
in hostility but we are going
to do it in strength.
>> you can try to beat us but
you won't be able to stop us
because we're going to rise to
the people that we are.
>> I need everybody to have an
understanding to that.
>> oh, thank you, MR. Chandler
let's hear from our next
speaker, please.
Just a reminder to hold your
applause and just signal that
you support somebody or hi, my
name is on that line a
descendant of DR. Espanola
jackson and I am here with
citywide herd alliance and I
have issues with I'm disabled
the elevators are always broke.
>> west point as well view
there are bugs everywhere rats,
roaches.
>> mice am coming out the stove
the deborah alice griffin was
red tagged I don't think
everybody knew about that but
it was red tagged so there is
people in there that need help
to get up out of there right
now the elevators don't work,
the city shut them down
and west point and in alice
griffith and we really do need
the mayor to come out and walk
with us and see the living
conditions that it is because I
know when the elevator broke I
stay in the house.
>> why is that?
I live on the fifth floor.
>> I can't go down them stairs
and then is feces.
>> there's is just is is is
beyond me.
I wouldn't want a dog to live
like that, you know?
>> so we really need you guys
and I appreciate the
supervisors here.
Simon all of all of you
appreciate you and I know you
guys are listening and I'm just
waiting to see what's going to
happen next.
>> think thank you.
Thank you.
Thank you for your comments.
>> all right.
Let's hear from our next
speaker.
Welcome.
Hi, I'm announcer lee.
I'm from thomas paine square.
It's atrocious how we live
and nobody wants to help us.
>> I asked either one of you to
come down here.
It's been 3 to 6 months living
there and see this and not have
been in san francisco.
It should not happen the way we
live roaches, rats, lords.
Yes jim is falling down.
Yes I believe now I'm calling
on you.
You represent our district.
>> we have been and I'm going
to pass your calling.
You and no retire.
i'm pausing your time and you
got voted in you can your
statements to the board as a
whole.
>> david powers thank you.
We need help and we're asking
you to do what you're supposed
to do and hold them accountable
.
>> thank you for your comments
just you service are in my
memory so you begin my
apologies.
>> I don't mean to interrupt
you.
It's just your addressing the
board as a whole, not
individual.
This is a meeting of the board
of supervisors.
So as the previous speaker
addressed a supervisor let's
address your comments to the to
everyone.
>> all right.
Welcome, ma'am.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
I'm from thomas paine square
also I've been in thomas paine
for over 50 years.
>> I have been there, seen
managers come and go.
They treat us like we love rats
and what it roaches and stuff
we have going through we have
mold in our apartments and they
say it's not mold.
>> they say it's from the cars
and stuff.
>> I stay in a three bedroom
and I haven't seen a mold in my
toilet.
I wash it out.
I clean.
>> my kitchen is still come
back.
I can mop the floor is still
there.
>> I say what is going on here?
and then when I call I can't
get them.
I have never seen a management
company.
They stay close every wednesday
they have training why every
you see do they have to have
training?
>> we need help and if we don't
get it sooner or later it's
going to be a whole lot of ill
going on in thomas paine.
>> thank you.
Thank you for your comments.
>> all right.
Let's hear from welcome.
Hello.
Yeah, my name is pat cochran
and I have the pleasure of
organizing with the thomas
paine tenants for the last
three years and with the hud
satellite city wide alliance
for I guess over six months
now.
And just to follow up on the
two last public comments.
Everything you could think
terrible about thomas paine.
Like every time I think I've
heard the worst thing I learn
something new.
We have seniors stuck on third
floor residents who cannot walk
down the stairs have been stuck
in their units for four months.
Certain supervisors haven't
returned calls about that.
But let's be real we have tenet
like we have the management is
trying to steal rent from folks
unless you're a resident who
has, you know, a whole series
of receipts about your rent,
they're trying to take money
from these folks.
There's people get threatened
with gun violence in this
complex.
There is lead paint.
there's a space stoves they had
people removing asbestos
without even protection like
everything you think terrible
you know this happens at thomas
paine there was even one
resident who was stuck on the
third floor who to get down
stairs had to get on her
and scoot stair by stair down
cement and in steel
and concrete stairs.
That is disgusting.
If that was your grandma you
would be up in arms.
So I begged this board to
please do something about this
because these residents have
been dealing with so much stuff
and over the last year or two
it's gotten a lot worse
and unless something happens
it's bad stuff is going to
happen at thomas paine.
So I please beg you to do
something about it.
>> thank you.
Thank you for your comments.
>> another speaker welcome.
Hi, my name is janelle jolley.
I'm a district eight resident
and I'm here in solidarity with
the citywide hud alliance.
I first want to thank a
supervisor for walton for his
leadership and holding the
initial hearing on APRIL 7th to
shine a light on the deplorable
conditions that many of our
neighbors in hud housing
throughout the city are forced
to endure.
The majority of the residents
at thomas paine specifically
are african-american
and working class.
These are people who labor
in the city.
These are people who hold our
communities together and they
are subject to some of the
worst housing abuses that
anyone has to endure in this
city and that's unacceptable
in the city of san francisco.
We love to tout how how we love
diversity.
We love inclusion.
We we work toward toward
equity.
But year after year these
residents and residents
throughout hud housing continue
to be abused by thuggish
management.
They are hounded such that they
get so frustrated living here
that they eventually leave
and that's unacceptable.
I'm calling on mayor daniel
lurie to show up and see how
these people live and do
something about it.
These residents deserve the
same amount of attention
and respect as anyone living
in the marina in the dogpatch
and then in other gentrifying
areas of the city.
We're also calling on the
supervisors who represent the
districts where there are hud
housing to show up
and represent your residents.
These people are depending on
you to ensure the respect
and dignity of their of their
families and of their entire
communities.
>> thank you.
Thank you for your comments.
>> we have another speaker
in your group.
All right.
Welcome MR. Washington ace on
the case the fillmore corridor
in bethesda.
>> and please put some respect
on in MAY because this official
been doing this for 14 years.
so let's talk about public
housing.
>> I go way, way, way back
before rad with the david
gilmore so I know what's
happening in all the different
managements that's been going
on in all the millions of
dollars that's been spent
and these residents keep coming
back, keep coming back
generation that the generation
that I'm in I'm 70 years old
when I got in the game I was
just barely 40 and the same
thing happens west in addition,
I stayed at thomas paine with
my family for years plaza east
and I was there when they tore
them down.
They want to build them back up
again but they got to spend
money $10 million to service
them.
>> alice griffin I was back
there in years when they when
they tried to put things
together.
John stewart all these ro
billionaire millionaires we go
check them we don't check them
you're not getting the way the
mayor I say he was a
millionaire but he's a
billionaire he's got to care
you just gotten office bella
and we're giving you a chance
and the mayor you got 30 days.
You got a few more weeks.
They told me give us 30 days.
We going to clean up fillmore?
>> we can't wait for the
addition.
>> well, your days are ticking
down and I'm coming out with my
report the unfinished agenda,
the all these reports that it's
starting to feel warm and the
bayview so so city y'all beware
.
i call it city hall but you
know I also call it silly hall
these on a case I'm on the case
here.
>> you ain't getting away with
it this time.
Thank you for your comments.
>> another speaker welcome
paying homage to all of the
speakers that came before me.
I want to recognize their
courage, their tenacity, their
determination in their
commitment to this beautiful
city we call san francisco.
My name is damian posey.
I'm the executive director
and founder of a youth
leadership and violence
prevention organization.
Call us for us primarily based
in the bayview but we serve the
whole city.
We serve the whole bay also
have the pleasure of being the
CHAIRMAN Of the southeast
public utilities commission
over there at 1550.
Evans but first and foremost
I'm a born and raised san
franciscan you know, primarily
in alice griffith double rock
one of the housing projects we
are talking about today.
Then I moved to fillmore when I
was around 1011 years old.
I lived all over the city.
I was born to a young mother so
I've been able to see things
all over the city and being
in a quote unquote leadership
position over there the
southeast I want to employer
and poor my fellow community
servants because that's what we
all are in here is community
service.
You know, and I definitely want
to pay homage and thank you so
much for your leadership,
sherman I know it's hard
especially being the only
brother over there, you know
what I'm saying?
Standing up for the people I
accept each and every one of
you guys every one of you
supervisors here scuse me.
Listen wholeheartedly to these
people.
If you have a heart, if you
care about san francisco, these
things are real.
I don't I don't live in age you
know more I work hard.
I'm, you know, got some other
things going on but I'm there
every day all day I'm there
with the people with the
community, those that know us
for us working with the young
people you see the camaraderie
up here.
It's not like that with our
young people.
We got people feel more here
honda's point there barack the
young people can't stand like
that together and part of the
issue is the living conditions
that they're living in that's
upsetting them and that's
causing problems.
But people don't look at it
like that.
The beef in the streets come
from things like this.
If I'm living in a commute,
where are you comfortable to be
outside.
>> thank you, MR. Posey for the
listener and let's take back
action.
Thank you for your comments.
You have to do with your
community.
We don't have a situation you
don't generate another problem
this big.
>> thank you MR. Posey.
>> we're setting the timer for
two minutes so everyone has
equal opportunity to speak.
>> is there another speaker
in your group?
>> okay.
No, sir.
Sorry.
You come back next week.
All right?
All right, we'll wait.
She said no.
>> come on up, sir.
You ready?
We're going to set the timer.
Here we go.
>> oh, good afternoon,
everyone.
I'm one of the case managers
for baby senior services and I
work directly at alice griffith
and I'm writing writing this
letter on behalf of the
residents of alice rivers.
Alice griffith to express the
concern and frustration over
the deteriorating living
conditions in our community
despite repeated efforts to
voice these issues, there have
been little to no meaningful
meaningful response from the
city leadership our residents
many of whom are seniors,
families with children
and excuse me family of
children, individual
individuals with disabilities
are endure enduring unsafe
and unacceptable circumstances
the presence of rats
and roaches throughout the
complex pose a serious health
risk and many buildings are
visibly collapsing or suffering
from structural damage that has
been has gone unaddressed for
far too long to make.
To make matters worse, seniors
and disabled residents are
unable to use elevators due to
unresolved billing disputes
which the city has failed to
resolve.
This lack of accessibility is
not only an inconvenience it is
discriminatory and places an
undue burden on our most
vulnerable neighbors.
>> to make matters worse,
seniors and disabled residents
are unable to use the elevators
due to unresolved excuse me two
minutes.
>> I'm just saying your 20s a
lot of people in the community
are, you know, really stressed
out.
It's very is making the
community restless.
We are looking to you know, to
get this whole thing situated
that way we can, you know, live
our lives.
How are we supposed to the
seniors can be safe and the
community we can be safe.
>> we can prevent black on
black crime and the things that
kills.
>> I can thank you.
Thank you so much for your
comments.
Is there anyone else in your
group?
All right.
Welcome, sir.
>> yes, thank you.
I've been coming before this
committee, this supervisors
board and these issues have
been a part of my dialog with
you and advocating for
different communities,
different districts in bayview
on this point, MR. Walton, I've
talked to him about this very
same issue when he was running
for the board as supervisor he
was at a tenant association
meeting.
It was griffith tried to bring
this attention to him and not
only him not put my finger to
him but this has been a city
hard collaborative effort to
deny and neglect those things
that hard require by law in the
in its call 4381 revision two
and it's the management agent
handbook and what I will read
from you to read from this
handbook from you is this is
from hud and it's ironic that
you got a hood alliance and all
these things are happening
and they have this type of
literature and oversight policy
declaration in law on their
books that they require
management of corporations to
be honored by us by if they are
signatory to that they'll
agreement that they suppose of
a deal you know, certain you
speak directly into the
microphone so we can hear you.
But as to those policies
and degradation that's in this
the management agent book I'm a
go to a pdf a number four
and it's called working with
residents.
>> I'm just going to read you
let's see this is a general 4.1
I know I don't have time to go
through all of this but
everything that you've spoken
about up to this point is is
can be dealt with through hud's
policy declarations in law.
That's in this very handbook.
So this is nothing new.
You know, and the people who
are in position of decision
and policy they're supposed to
be all over the city and county
of san francisco.
Thank you, sir.
>> thank you for your comments.
is there anyone else in your
group as everyone spoken all
right.
>> oh, listen, seniors,
welcome.
Let's hear from our next
speaker.
>> greetings, PRESIDENT.
Our supervisor shamar walton on
the board as well as reverend
amos brown, bishop birch
and the MAY was all the ones
from the community who was
coming out to speak is still
fighting.
We are still fighting even
after mother espanola is gone.
These young boys these old moms
we are still fighting for our
public housing.
I'm a third generation for
alice griffith but at the end
of the day alice griffith has
three elevators that's there
and I hope all of you guys had
a wonderful weekend and enjoyed
your easter.
You know and if you know the
meaning of easter I hope you
enjoyed it even more because
in alice griffith two elevators
are out.
They have five floors
and residents want it to be
with their family.
Their family wanted to be with
them but because the elevators
were out been out with one been
out three weeks, another one
been out for a whole year, they
were not able to do that.
Not only that when you're stuck
in there and not knowing about
it, you can call the fire
department, you know, so they
could take them down and bring
them back up.
You can call your your primary
care doctor in case you have an
appointment to take you to your
point I mean to contact your
social worker so they can have
a hammer or have the arm the
other emt come get them
and take them to their
appointment, you know, but not
knowing this we're just stuck.
We don't even get wellness
check.
What is wellness check?
That has not happened.
This is not okay.
This is not acceptable.
We are steady being on our
supervisor back daniel laurie
from what I understand he want
to bring more people in the
community, take care of our
community first.
Take care of us before you
brings other thank you for your
comments.
All right.
We're going to move to the next
group of speakers.
I'm I want to thank you all for
your patience and waiting for
this organized group to make
their statements and now we'll
hear from you all and we're
setting the timer for two
minutes.
>> here we go.
My name is laura krs-one.
I'm the executive director of
the arab resource
and organizing center.
I also sit on the racial equity
council for the planning
department and I want to start
by saying we stand
in solidarity with the citywide
hud alliance and their demands
and requests of you and hope
that they are able to live
and thrive in this city
alongside everybody else.
We also stand in solidarity
with seiu 2015 who were here
sharing remarks earlier.
absolutely.
I'm here also with some
colleagues to thank you all for
introducing a resolution to
honor arab-american heritage
month and specifically to thank
supervisor bilal mahmood for
introducing the resolution as
well as a resolution to stand
against collaborations racial
discriminatory collaborations
with the federal government,
arab-american heritage and our
community contributions in this
country go back over 150 years.
>> this long history is sadly
unknown by many overlooked
and erased through some
xenophobic perceptions that the
current PRESIDENT Is parroting
now in a grueling political
climate and with this country's
federal administration putting
a target on our backs arab
communities in san francisco
and across the country are
facing unpaid resident levels
of state repression racial,
political and religious
discrimination and hate
violence.
>> over the last year and a
half arab families in the city
have endured immense trauma as
we watch family members,
friends and broader community
suffer unspeakable atrocities
and as which they continue to
endure.
All the while we're faced with
unprecedented hate violence
and discrimination right here
in this city only for being
palestinian or speaking out for
being palestinian like the
historic record number of
people who gave public comment
last year in this chambers
in support of a cease fire
resolution that you supported.
we appreciate you all our
elected leaders for taking the
right call in this moment for
standing for peace and against
discrimination.
And we hope that you will
continue to ensure that all
people are protected and free
from harm against any racially
discriminatory policies
and supporting the most
vulnerable.
>> thank you for your comments.
>> let's welcome our next
speaker.
>> good afternoon supervisors.
My name is muhammad check.
I'm the organizing director of
the arab resource
and organizing center.
I also just want to state that
I am in full solidarity with
the citywide hud alliance
and their demands for fair
and dignified housing.
>> mean I'm here today to thank
you for introducing and hearing
the resolution to honor
arab-american heritage month
and specifically supervisor
mahmood for putting forward
this resolution.
This month serves to honor our
resilience and as a reminder
that supporting the arab
and swanwick communities is
central right now in the fight
against bigotry
and intolerance.
The acknowledgment of
arab-american heritage comes at
a crucial time.
As many of you know, arab iraq
organizers bay area youth ages
14 to 22 now locally
and nationally we are
witnessing our young community
members being not only punished
for speaking out against war,
genocide and repression but
diverse immigrant students are
being abducted and disappeared
by ice simply for choosing to
speak up against war
and genocide in palestine.
>> this is part of a broader
attack on immigrants.
>> this is why iraq is proud to
have worked for years
in multiracial coalitions
in this city to support
and advocate on behalf of
immigrant communities.
So as we're working right now
alongside many to ensure
community defense, the attacks
on our communities make clear
that this current federal
administration is working to
make an example out of arabs,
muslims and anyone who speaks
in support of palestine for how
it plans to squash any kind of
dissent.
>> yet our resilience in the
face of injustice is central to
our here honoring today.
So I thank you for taking time
to honor our resilience and for
thank you for your comments.
So welcome our next speaker.
>> good afternoon supervisors.
My name is fadel rahman.
I operate two businesses in san
francisco, one of which is a
retail outlet food outlet
in the tenderloin.
>> the other one is a wholesale
outlet at the bayview hunters
point.
>> I am here to thank
supervisor mahmood for bringing
up the legislation and to
recognize the existence, the
positive and productive
existence of arabs in san
francisco who have been here
for more than 100 years.
>> we are an organization as a
business.
>> we are organization
neighborhood business alliance
with about 1000 members
in here.
We work with the city.
Revenues are up.
Taxes and we work hard.
We work positive.
We are in all spectrums of the
city here.
We are professionals.
We are businesses.
We are doctors, common workers.
>> and we really appreciate
each and every one of you for
recognizing our existence
in here.
So positivity and productivity
can go on.
>> thank you very much.
Thank you for your comments.
>> let's welcome our next
speaker.
Thank you honorable
supervisors.
Thank you supervisor bilal
and our own community members
and staff and city hall for
drafting this resolution
and all you do to make sure we
have a seat at the table.
My name is maryam.
I have served the city
and county of san francisco as
a commissioner on the small
business commission for nearly
a decade.
>> I grew up at a corner store
and deli walkable to city hall
and in a small business
community that is deeply
involved in the social
and civic fabric of this city.
I also grew up as a young arab
organizer working with our
community groups advocating for
things like the language access
ordinance and safe, safe civil
rights ordinance which is now
being voted on today
and resurfacing as an important
issue.
>> thank you all for taking
that on during my time on the
small business commission.
I have made an effort to sunset
a number of outdated
and discriminatory policies
that reveal themselves through
the legislative history of the
corner store and nuisance
abatement laws.
I'm grateful to the supervisor
as outgoing current I knew
especially supervisor walton
who have been tackling these
harmful codes and taking off
the books several broken window
style laws that punish working
and poor communities and create
hostile regulatory environments
for as fadal one of our members
mentioned over 1000 arab
businesses in this city.
>> however, we still have a
long way to go before we break
the double standard of who the
city serves and whom it
punishes.
>> I'm proud to share public
comment today with other small
businesses and we are proud to
be part of one of the bay
area's longest continuous
merchant organizations.
>> I'm also proud to be with my
arab and palestinian community
and glad to see the armenian
genocide resolution on today's
agenda as well.
And I'm here to remind you that
you do not have to hold the
federal party line.
>> we are your constituents
and we ask you to give us as
you vote on this symbolic
resolution the respect we
deserve and the material change
we have been fighting to see.
>> thank you.
thank you, commissioners.
For your comments.
>> hello supervisors.
My name is nadir.
I'm a resident of district one.
I'm here today to give a
comment on the resolution
recognizing arab-american
heritage month.
>> thank you so much to
supervisor mahmud for
introducing this resolution
and to all of you who stepped
forward to sponsor it as well
recognizing this observance
in this moment in time is
especially critical.
>> we are one and a half years
into the genocide in gaza.
>> in addition to being a moral
disaster this the genocide
in gaza has caused the worst
anti-arab racism in the united
states that I've seen in my 39
years of life here.
>> on top of that we have a
presidential administration who
is targeting people based on
their advocacy for the arab
community here in the united
states specifically for
palestinian human rights.
We are living in a time when
people are literally being
taken off the streets and being
disappeared without having
broken any laws.
>> visas of international
students are being canceled for
exercising their right to free
speech in this country.
These people are predominant
arab people and their allies
arab americans are being
discriminated against daily
in the streets of san francisco
so they are experiencing hate
daily.
Somebody outside when I was
right before I came through
security today to give public
comment told me to go back to
my country because I am wearing
a cafe which is a symbol of
palestinian culture.
>> stuff like this is happening
all the time but people do not
feel safe coming forward
and reporting those incidents.
Our community organizations are
hearing both incidents.
Iraq is hearing about those
incidents.
Kerry is hearing about those
incidents but they're not
making it into police reports
because this community feels
under attack and they do not
feel safe.
>> so that comes down to what
you can do in addition to
voting for this today, standing
with the arab community means
standing up to bullies who want
you to remain silent and do not
want you to signify.
>> thank you for your comments.
If you have something you'd
like to hand over we can place
that in our minutes.
Just an offer to you.
>> let's hear from our next
speaker please.
Good afternoon, supervisors.
>> good to see you all.
Thank you, PRESIDENT
Mendelsohn.
Thank you.
Our supervisor mahmood bilal
for putting together this
resolution.
It is now more important than
ever.
For those of you that don't
know me, my name is mario
moghadam and I've worked with
many of you but owner of the
puzzle chase for 30 some odd
years past PRESIDENT Of west
portal merchants association
and PRESIDENT Emeritus meritus
of the council of district
merchants and currently
PRESIDENT Of avenue greenlight.
>> but what many of you don't
know or MAY not know is that I
am an immigrant.
The palestinian immigrant.
English is my second language
and I am here living the
american dream.
And I encourage you to do
events like this and make
resolutions like this because
there are in my course of
working with the communities
in the city I've run into so
many what I call invisible
arabs or quiet arabs that
slowly contributes to community
peace volunteer their time,
support their supervisors are
politically active but most of
you don't even realize who we
are because we are so quiet
because there is a stigma.
>> we're slowly but surely
overcoming this stigma.
And thank you for this
resolution and it is more
important now than ever to be
able to do it because hopefully
next year when the
arab-american community comes
before you they'll be hundreds
of us or plenty of us.
Just like what we saw the
resolution for grace or corey
who I've worked with many times
before and love to see the
recognition that she got which
was well deserved.
So thank you.
Keep this up.
Let's let's do more.
There are many more of us that
can come out because I am an
immigrant.
>> english is my second
language but I'm also a proud
san franciscan and proud to be
in america.
And honestly if anyone ever
told me to go home my response
always is I wish.
>> thank you.
Thank you.
I'll yield my time.
Thank you for your comments.
Welcome to our next speaker.
>> good afternoon supervisors.
My name is tatiana rathore.
I'm a community advocate on the
civil liberties and community
safety program at the asian law
caucus.
I'm honored to be directly
supporting low income immigrant
communities of color through
our work at aoc.
>> as an organization with
decades of history defending
the rights of arab middle
eastern muslim and south asian
communities, we know firsthand
the devastating impact that
government surveillance
and data collection based on
religion or ethnicity can have.
>> communities of color have
long been targeted under the
guise of national security.
From nine years in the early
2000s to the muslim ban during
trump's first presidency to
ongoing surveillance programs
like the joint terrorism task
force which he wrote local
oversight of san francisco
police.
>> now in trump's second term,
these attacks continue.
Where for example, my student
visa revocations that a recent
lawsuit says disproportionately
target african muslim middle
eastern and asian students.
I would like to thank the board
members sponsoring the
resolution reaffirming our
city's noncooperation with
identity based registries
and directing more attention to
the civil liberties risks of
participating in programs like
the jttf.
>> with the current
administration's continued
labeling of immigrants as
invaders and subhuman, we need
the government of the city
and county of san francisco as
a critical line of defense.
If personal highly sensitive
data is collected or shared
with federal authorities, it
could be weaponized to enable
racial profiling in detention
and other violations of civil
rights.
>> now is a crucial time to
reaffirm our city's
noncooperation with identity
based registries as so many
vulnerable community members
are being targeted based on
their identities.
On behalf of aoc, I urge the
board of supervisors to vote
in support of this resolution.
>> thank you.
Thank you for your comments.
Next speaker.
>> good afternoon board of
supervisors.
For the record, my name is
christopher klein.
I also go by sergeant klein of
the united states marine corps.
I hope each of you had an
enjoyable easter.
I attended multiple churches,
attended the cherry blossom
parade and volunteered at the
unitarian church with a
community dinner.
But that's not what brought me
here.
I wanted to talk about a few
things.
there's a state sponsored
terrorism fund of $120 billion.
And I've heard every excuse
from the city attorney's office
.
The last one was that it was a
republican fund set up.
And that is not true.
The fund was set up in 2015
under PRESIDENT Obama.
There is a communication
and technology breakdown here
that needs to be fixed
rectified by the fcc, doj, dhs
and the department of defense.
For example, if the castro
attacked just yesterday were a
brutal attack that was caused
by a communication technology
breakdown that needs to be
fixed immediately.
It's very easy.
The previous speaker spoke
about surveillance technology.
You need to talk to the city
attorney's office about that
because the city attorney's
office is doing that as well.
And finally I sent an email to
each of you earlier today
and other key stakeholders
within the city and county of
san francisco concerning this
and other topics.
Please read that email.
Get with public health public
safety set up meetings
immediately to discuss the
overutilization and access or
credentials being issued to
people that shouldn't have
access to these systems.
What public health is doing is
interfering with public safety
and vice versa.
It's an easy fix.
It's literally a three second
fix that needs to be coded to
turn it off.
We all need to have san
francisco back to where it was.
I love san francisco.
I love the street festivals.
I love the people here.
We can get it back but it's
going to need an all in all
hands approach by everybody
in this room, including the
people that spoke here earlier.
So thank you.
>> thank you for your comments.
Next speaker.
>> hello.
>> I'm here in solidarity with
the black community and the
arab community.
>> also a guy has been sitting
behind me and standing behind
me calling people.
Just letting you know it's an
event.
Mm.
>> so we're kind of in the
middle of this anti harm
reduction debate and the
mayor seems to already be
committed to rolling back some
harm reduction tools like the
foil and straws which I learned
that if you smoke fentanyl it's
safer than if you inject it.
So by taking that away you are
forcing people to take on more
risk with their health
and their lives.
>> there's so much data behind
harm reduction which is led
with compassion and backed up
by science that I seriously
wonder what your decisions
would be if we could charge you
with murder for knowingly
putting people's lives at risk.
>> would you still co-sponsor
or support recovery first?
If we the people could hold you
accountable for doing this to
us for literally your right.
>> I see a lot of similarities
between the anti-armor duction
and the anti trans movement
in america.
There is a denial of science.
There is a denial of reality
and there is a denial of
diversity in humanity.
>> humans are very diverse.
That's just nature.
That is reality.
And so we need to account for
all of the diversity we have as
a species.
There's a denial of equity for
those most marginalized those
who can't afford to pay for
their own recovery programs or
spores or whatever that
literally do rely on street
programs and there's a denial
of inclusion, an inclusion of
science backed harm reduction
methods.
>> you know what the?
Thank you for your comments.
Next speaker.
>> nick forever silvio.
Uh, first I like to say I think
a supervisor moves to the hill
in the evening so people are
going to turn them who aren't
working all day.
You MAY have heard of my
situation.
I attempted to publicize it's
another big helped in case I've
been a victim for ten years of
organized crime.
Whoever is doing it to me
mostly by some kind of
satellite technology I'm
attacked all the physically,
mentally and property wise
and not able to find help
anywhere.
I've contacted the san
francisco police many times
in recent years hospitals,
social workers, other city
agencies and not helping
anything.
barely able to live.
I'm being attacked so badly by
the technology all day and by
operatives on the street as
well.
Um I don't know.
I believe I'm being attacked
mostly for free speech or
fascism whatever we are living
under.
Maybe you can explain what
we're living under in any case,
I'm not being helped by the
city.
Three of the ten years I've
been in san francisco and seven
in the east bay and as far as
I'm aware it would be the S.F.
Pd's job to be happy to be a
primary city in any case
and having helped in any way.
So I would appeal to the
supervisors to help me and or
tell me where I can find help
within the city.
No comment.
>> or are we living under
fascism?
So this is your opportunity to
provide your comment to the
board of supervisors we're
listening to explain I'm not
being helped by I'm not finding
help here in the city.
So I was asking where in the
city I can find help.
What I'll do is I'll have
someone come and take your
information and and get more
clearly what it is you're
looking for.
So if you'll have a seat in the
first row.
Thank you.
Welcome back to our next
speaker.
>> good afternoon.
As a start I was a driver for
over that drove to stanford
university delivering on
santacon, a northern california
district excuse me northern
district court of california 25
hyphen cv hyphen 03477 filed
APRIL 21st yesterday year 2025
I did not file that that court
case is over comma ftc v
period.
>> federal trade commission I
have a united states passport
recently san francisco state
university and other
universities have visas
canceled and revoked and final
statement is apec asia-pacific
economic coordination.
So if over when globalized with
mentioning of united states of
america dollar china trade
china shipping and recession it
over went into the philippines
if uber was out of uber hub
in daly city what mission
connected with district nine
all the way to daly city if
that's your or san jose so then
we're off from district nine no
evali or then where of to that
border thank you sincerely
thank you for your comments.
>> welcome to our next speaker
.
This MAY make which might this
would you hear me?
That's fine.
Good.
Hi david stoller.
I'm the founder of two to
international tenants union
and let's get right down to
business.
We were founded on indigenous
peoples day weekend.
I'm not lying when I was
campaigning to reelect my
wonderful dean preston as
supervisor when polluted water
came into our building I
happened to have found the
david and goliath landscape
solutions, the legendary
irrigation landscape company
in seattle on earth day 1991.
Quite a while ago before I
relocated here a couple of
years ago.
So I know a lot about water.
I've sat on international
panels on water when the
polluted water came in I knew
what was happening 311 said
call randy shaw.
Call randy shaw your slumlord
and he will take care of it.
>> well, randy sure didn't take
care of it.
I sure I was certain the city
would find him there.
He was supposed to hire an
emergency plumber to keep the
polluted water from these
broken water mains out of our
building.
He didn't do it the city
and find him.
>> and then in my working with
aaron peskin, the PRESIDENT
Campaigning for jackie fielder
thank you.
>> and my vision is a little
obscure right now so if I don't
see any of the wonderful people
I've had the honor of meeting
thank you and those who I
haven't met yet.
Thank you.
I hope that you will take this
matter seriously.
We need criminal enterprises
like tenderloin housing clinic
to be removed from what they're
doing because they are
violating federal law by having
drug addicts live at our
buildings for free at the
expense of the american
taxpayer.
One of those drug addicts
assaulted me a few days ago.
>> I'm well known to the
police.
I call them all the time.
I've developed a good
relationship with them.
Unfortunately everybody I've
tried or in touch with the
mayor all the time and thank
you for your comments.
I love you.
The city of santa barbara for
their speakers time is
concluded except this guy
and I'll be in touch with you
all.
Thank you.
Thank you for your comments.
Our muslim is welcome to our
next speaker activists good
afternoon supervisors my name
is deepa patel.
I'm a first generation hotelier
in san francisco taking this
opportunity at city hall today
with my son who's 18 senior as
a spring break little break
since we had a hearing at city
hall regarding a matter that I
want to bring to your attention
that I've I've come to several
of your offices and spoke about
brea very briefly but I want to
take this opportunity to say
show that one voice can matter
that the vacancy tax laws that
have been in place are in fact
hurting small businesses like
myself who have done the right
thing by not allowing rents to
be able to rent to small like
half liquor stores or mini
marts that have polluted our
city with the ability to have
crime in the area because of
those stores and because we've
left it vacant or in my
particular case a construction
zone on sixth street for
several years now we're being
taxed out because we're a
vacancy.
now it seems that there's only
four exemptions and none of
those apply to me except for
one which I did receive an
exemption for one of the spaces
for a fire the other space
because I rent it to a tenant
the tenant thereafter sued me
because I did disclose that
construction was going to
happen on the city sidewalks
that I ended up evicting him
because that's as a landlord I
need to collect rent if you're
in my space.
He ended up hiring a pro bono
law firm and ended up making a
claim for $500,000 and now we
close out that case and moved
on.
Now the city has used that time
frame of the vacancy to tax as
$4,500 plus penalty of 2000
plus dollars.
>> it seems unfair that an area
that's riddled with open drug
use, heavy construction and all
kinds of economic damage that
we as landlords be held to to
pay for these vacancy taxes I
think there should be
exemptions.
>> thank you for your comments
like to say what a wonderful
job it's going to be.
Thank you thank you for your
comments.
Welcome to our next speaker,
MR. Almond I hope all of you
are in good health.
I want to thank former
mayor london breed for doing an
excellent job and I would like
to thank dean preston, my
supervisor of district five.
I also like to thank matt haney
when it was district six.
Congratulations since to
stephanie who is in the
assembly in sacramento.
please correct me if I'm
incorrect.
I also like to thank very much
our former PRESIDENT Aaron
peskin and also hillary rodham
.
>> thank you MS..
Melgar, wherever you are that
this is emergency procedures
and I looked at over and I, I
think it's p r t to go to the
fire department and learn how
when we have an earthquake to
be prepared.
Now the word affordable is
unacceptable and I found this
new affordable homes for sale
in soma soma affordable it's
not $100,850 another one two
persons 150,000 and 303 person
120,001 to 120,704 person
144,105 person 155,000 is 650.
There needs to be low income
and section eight I've said it
over and over then we have the
lsat which is outrageous.
>> so thank you for your time.
Happy easter too.
Happy pesach.
You look all of you are doing a
wonderful job and I thank you
for your time today.
>> thank you MR. Amen for your
comments.
Let's hear from our next
speaker.
Welcome.
>> hello.
Thank you.
My name is rocio molina.
I'm here from the san francisco
human services network.
I am here to share information
about the nonprofit sector's
need for your support during
this critical project process.
We are waiting on the edge of
our seats to receive critical
updates about what our
budgeting will look like for
the next year for the next two
years and to really collaborate
as partners with department
heads and all of you here today
to strategize around the most
critical needs of our
communities which the nonprofit
sector is perfectly positioned
to inform and to support on the
way over here.
>> I was able to listen in a
little bit and I I heard the
gentleman implore you all for
support on the street and he
was here asking for a referral
asking for guidance and I can
almost guarantee you that he is
going to be referred to one of
our nonprofit partners in the
community who provide the most
life saving and critical
services to you all and to our
community members.
And I really hope that we can
place the critical value that
they provide with the budget as
well in mind.
>> we are asking for a cost of
doing business increase to
include food, a consideration
of the increased inflation that
we are all experiencing.
Our nonprofits cannot provide
the critical services that they
have been providing at the same
cost due to inflation.
Meals costs more, housing costs
more.
I've been hearing a lot about
ensuring insurance costs going
up.
These are all things that they
would like to share with all of
you and I hope that your ears
are open.
>> thank you.
Thank you for your comments.
Are there any other members of
the public who would like to
address the board during
general public comment?
Great.
Come on up, sir.
If no one else lines up then
this will be our last speaker.
>> welcome.
>> good afternoon.
Board PRESIDENT And board of
supervisors.
My name is richard sd peterson.
I'll make it really short.
I still haven't got my fortune
telling permit and giving up my
law practice and I'm basically
unemployed and I need your
help.
And so as you can see, I've
become a shill for one of my
former clients.
>> that's all.
Have a wonderful weekend.
Thank you for your comments.
All right, MR. PRESIDENT.
All right.
Public comment is now closed.
>> MADAM Clerk, let's go to our
for adoption without committee
reference.
Agenda items 15 through 27
items 15 through 27 were
introduced for adoption without
committee reference.
A unanimous vote is required
for adoption of a resolution on
first reading today.
Alternatively a member MAY
require a resolution on first
reading to go to committee.
>> supervisor mahmud.
>> I'd like to request four
items number 18 and 21 to be
severed to be read separately.
>> okay.
Supervisor walton thank you
PRESIDENT MADAM and I just want
to make sure that I'm added as
a co-sponsor of item 18.
>> okay, MADAM Clerk, you can
take care of that.
Yes, you're on.
all right.
Can you call the roll on the
balance of the items just to
confirm supervisor.
MR. PRESIDENT, 18 and 1918
and 21.
18 and 21.
All right.
So then on items 15 through 17,
19 2020 two, 23, 24, 25, 2627
supervise her chin chin I
supervisor dorsey dorsey eyes
supervisor and guardian
and guardian eyes supervisor
fielder fielder I supervisor
mahmood mahmood I supervisor
middleman hi middleman I
supervisor melgar melgar I
supervisor sorter sorter I
supervisor cheryl cheryl I
supervisor walton I walton I
and supervisor chen chan either
are 11 eyes without objection
the resolutions are adopted
and motions are approved.
MADAM Clerk can you please call
item 18?
>> item 18 this is a resolution
to recognize the month of APRIL
2025 as arab american heritage
month in the city and county of
san francisco.
>> supervisor mahmood thank you
colleagues.
I wanted to briefly speak on my
resolution for the city of
county san francisco
celebrating arab-american
heritage month air americans
have made a profound
and lasting contribution to the
cultural, social, economic
and political landscape of the
united states enriching the
nation's history with their
resilience, innovation
and creativity as we just heard
from so many of the community
members who came and spoke
during public comment today
and thank you to them for
raising awareness and asking
for this resolution as well.
Every american heritage month
observed in the month of APRIL
provides a significant
opportunity to honor
and celebrate the diverse
cultures, traditions
and histories of arab-americans
while promoting awareness
and understanding of the
arab-american communities
invaluable role in shaping
american society.
The arab-american community
in san francisco has a rich
and proud history of
contributing to the city's
diverse identity with
individuals and families from a
variety of arab nations such as
lebanon, syria, palestine,
egypt, iraq, jordan, yemen
and others.
>> building homes, businesses,
communities and the cities for
generations, district five is
home to a vibrant and thriving
arab-american communities where
residents from a wide array of
backgrounds and traditions have
made significant contributions
to the city's cultural
and social fabric.
>> just a week ago, with the
incredible support of the
community, we were able to pull
together the first ever largest
tenderloin each street fair
creating a space for our arab
community to shop local
retailers in a bazaar.
Enjoy live performance by
palestinian artist M.C.
And enjoy activities outdoors
with their children.
>> in this context now more
than ever it is important to
uplift our diverse communities
and to fight against
discrimination, xenophobia
and hate that we know and hear
so many of our community
members are facing.
And is time to affirm our
dedication to supporting
arab-americans and all
marginalized communities to
achieve equality and justice.
Thank you again to all the
community members that came out
and spoke and public comment
and thank you to my colleagues
for your unanimous support
and most importantly as well I
want to thank janice from
supervisor dorsey's office who
I know has been leading on
representation for the arab
and muslim community for many,
many years and is the aide who
actually wrote this resolution
and I want to thank her as well
for her contribution here.
>> thank you, supervisor dorsey
thank you PRESIDENT Randleman
and thank you supervisor
mahmood for I actually was
going to give you credit for
authoring the resolution but
thank you for being the lead
sponsor on it.
District six is proudly home to
many arab-americans and small
business owners who are deeply
woven into the fabric of our
neighborhoods from corner
stores and family run
restaurants to nonprofit
leaders and entrepreneurs.
The arab american community
in district six has long played
a vital role in sustaining our
local economy and strengthening
the cultural life of our city.
The resilience through the
challenging these challenging
times has helped to anchor our
communities and remind us of
the power of perseverance,
pride and service.
Today I'm proud to co-sponsor
this resolution declaring APRIL
as arab american heritage month
in san francisco.
This is long overdue
recognition of a community that
has been an integral part of
the american story
and certainly san francisco
story for generations arab
americans have contributed
immensely to the cultural,
economic and civic fabric of
our city often while facing
discrimination, erasure
and barriers to full belonging
.
This resolution seeks not only
to celebrate arab american
heritage but also to confront
that legacy of exclusion.
It is an affirmation of
identity history and the
vibrant cultural richness that
arab-americans bring to san
francisco from the arts to
academia, small business to
social justice movements,
public service to public health
it is also a statement of
solidarity and support for a
community that has far too
often been marginalized
and misunderstood.
So I want to take a moment to
acknowledge and thank my
legislative aide mohana ebadi,
who played a leading role
in drafting this resolution.
Muhanna is the only muslim
legislative aide currently
serving in city hall and she
has brought not just her
professional expertise but also
her deep personal passion for
equity, inclusion
and representation to this
work.
to those who know her, she is a
rock star.
Her commitment to uplifting
arab and muslim communities
through policy celebration
and visibility is something I
really admire and I'm grateful
every day to have her on our
team.
So I hope this resolution
serves as an enduring public
recognition that arab american
history is american history.
I am grateful to my colleagues
for joining us in celebrating
arab american history heritage
month and ensuring that san
francisco continues to be a
place where every culture is
honored, every voice is heard
and every san franciscan has a
seat at the table.
>> thank you.
Thank you.
Supervisor.
I think with that we can take
this item.
Same house, same call.
>> without objection the
resolution is adopted.
MADAM Clerk, can you please
call item 21?
>> item 21 this is a resolution
to affirm san francisco's
commitment to preserving black
indigenous and black people of
color and lesbian gay bisexual,
transgender questioning
history and to provide a
diverse, equitable, inclusive
and belonging environment for
its workers, residents
and visitors.
>> supervisor mahmud I just
want to thank again supervisor
walton and supervisor mandell
man and PRESIDENT For
introducing this resolution
and especially in the context
of the current trump
administration's weaponized
version of this issue and the
actions it is continuing to
take.
I also wanted to briefly
acknowledge a recent event that
came to light which was that
in the unfortunately in a
similar string of events to the
spirit of what's been
acknowledged in this
resolution.
Reverend brown had some of his
memorabilia removed from the
smithsonian and he was notified
of that last week and I think
compounding with a lot of the
issues that are happening
nationally we just wanted to
acknowledge that on the record
as having occurred and again
condemning these actions from
the federal administration as
they continue to eliminate
black bipoc broader arab
palestinian voices across the
across the spectrum.
And it's extremely troubling
these times.
And I just wanted to extend
again our gratitude to reverend
brown for all he's done for the
community and for the city
and how these issues should not
be occurring.
And we are here in support.
And thank you for that.
And with that we can take this
item same house, same call
without objection the
resolution is adopted and MADAM
Clerk, could you please.
Could you could you please read
the in memoriam?
>> yesterday's meeting will be
adjourned in memory of the
following beloved individual.
On behalf of supervisor walton
for the late MR. Otis winfield
jr.
>> thank you, MADAM Clerk.
I skipped over imperative
agenda but we do not have any
imperative agenda.
I have none to report.
All right.
And I think that brings us to
the end of our agenda.
>> do we have any further
business before us?
>> that concludes our business
for today.
Well then we are adjourned.
Thank you, MADAM Clerk